[](https://www.3plearning.com/)3P Learning

* [Districts and School GroupsFind the solutions and support to achieve your goals](http://www.3plearning.com/for-districts/)
* [Schools and TeachersFind blended learning tools for mathematics and literacy](http://www.3plearning.com/for-schools/)
* [Parents and Home UsersFind mathematics and literacy programs to bring a love of learning home](http://www.3plearning.com/for-home/)
* [Giving Back ProgramWe are passionate about providing 'Better Ways to Learn' to more students around the world. Learn more about our Giving Back Program.](https://www.3plearning.com/giving-back/)

By Subject* [MathematicsPrograms for early to secondary learners, covering everything from beginner’s numeracy to geometry, chance, and data.](https://www.3plearning.com/mathematics/)
* [LiteracyPrograms for early to secondary learners, covering everything from phonics, letters, and sounds, to etymology, orthography, and phonology.](https://www.3plearning.com/literacy/)

By Solution* [](http://www.3plearning.com/software/mathletics/)

    The comprehensive mathematics program

    The early learners introduction to the world of numeracy

    An effective learn-to-read program that students love.

    A systematic, time-saving writing program that develops essential writing skills and fosters an enjoyment of writing

    Powerful assessment for writing and maths that show visible proof of progress.

Packages* [](http://www.3plearning.com/3essentials/)

    An integrated package that combines our award-winning online learning programs for **reading**, **writing** and **maths** — at unbeatable value for your school

    The complete answer to school’s literacy needs

    The complete maths solution for student progress

* [Product SupportFind walkthroughs and guides for all of our programs](https://support.3plearning.com/)
* [Technical SupportFind minimum computer requirements, supported browsers and more](https://support.3plearning.com/tech)
* [WebinarsFind weekly webinars on how to get the most out of our programs](https://support.3plearning.com/webinar-schedules/)
* [Resource CenterFind a huge range of teacher-picked classroom resources](https://www.3plearning.com/resources/)
* [Curriculum AlignmentSee how our programs meet the requirements of your local curriculum](https://www.3plearning.com/curriculum/)
* [BlogFind our library of articles, resources and videos on education](https://www.3plearning.com/blog/)
* [Professional LearningDiscover our professional learning courses offered in Canada and the United States.](https://www.3plearning.com/professional-learning/)

* [World Maths DayThe World’s Largest Online Maths Competition is back!](https://www.3plearning.com/world-maths-day/)
* [InvestorsFind our investor portal, latest news and how to invest](https://www.3plearning.com/investors/)

    See your students improve with just 30 minutes of Mathletics a week

    Start a trial

    Start a trial

    Start a trial

    Request a Demo

    Get a quote

    Get a quote

    Get a quote

    Get a quote

    Start a trial

    Sign in

    Sign in

    Sign in

    Sign in

    Sign in

    Sign in

    Sign in

Privacy Policy
==============

**Last updated 22 April, 2024**

From the 3P Privacy Office
--------------------------

Dear Teachers, Parents and Friends,  
  
Our learning activities are designed for education purposes. We seek to harness the best elements of online learning to support educators and motivate children to succeed in reading, writing and mathematics.  
  
Our privacy policy has been reissued to add detail on updated product features.  
  
For the student users subscribed to Reading Eggs or Writing Legends, we added details on the features of free-text response activities and reading activities (school subscriptions only). Any personal information made available to us in our programs is only for education purposes and to deliver our engaging learning programs.  
  
Our Data Privacy and Security FAQs and Cookies and Third Party Technologies Policy have also been updated with added detail on how website analytics are used and can be managed by users.  
  
Thank you for being part of better ways to learn!  
  
If you have questions about our policy, please contact us at privacy@3plearning.com  
  
3P Privacy Office  
  
(22 April 2024)

At 3P Learning, we value your privacy and understand the importance of keeping your personal information secure.   We have this Privacy Policy to help you understand how we collect, store, use and remove the information that you provide us. 

About 3P Learning Ltd’s Privacy Policy
--------------------------------------

This policy explains our privacy and security commitments in plain language.

* 3P Learning is a global provider of e-learning resources. We produce a range of online resources and a network of websites including  [Mathletics](https://www.3plearning.com/software/mathletics/?), [Reading Eggs](https://www.3plearning.com/software/reading-eggs/?), [Mathseeds](https://www.3plearning.com/software/mathseeds/?), [Wordflyers](https://www.3plearning.com/software/wordflyers/?), [Writing Legends](https://www.writinglegends.com/?r=AU), [Storyathon,](https://www.storyathon.com/?r=AU)  [Teachers Workshop Series](https://teacherworkshopseries.com/?r=AU) and Brightpath Progress (collectively, the ‘**Site**’), and World Maths Day/ World Education Games branded resources and products.
* Each product or resource, together with challenge websites for national and regional events which may use or integrate with the Site, is owned and operated by the 3P Learning group of companies (including 3P Learning Limited, Blake eLearning Pty Ltd and their related entities and subsidiaries) (collectively, ‘**3P Learning’** or **‘us’** or **‘we**’). 
* References to the Site in this Privacy Policy include all 3P Learning products and resources that we produce and distribute.
* 3P Learning is committed to protecting the safety and security of our registered users, including students, teachers, school administrators and parents (collectively, **Registrants**) and we are sensitive to concerns about the safety of the personal information provided to us. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully in order to understand how any personal information collected by us is used.
* As a global company, our Privacy Policy has been developed in accordance with a range of legislation which applies to us. In addition, we have developed our privacy framework to assist our customers that are schools, districts and education bodies to comply with privacy legislation and regulations applicable to them and the way they manage personal information. 
* Collectively, this legislation includes, but is not limited to: 
    * The Australian Privacy Act 1988
    * The New Zealand Privacy Act 1993
    * The United Kingdom Data Protection Act 2018 ([View 3P Learning’s ICO Registration Certificate](https://pppmarketingcdn.blob.core.windows.net/docs/global/policy/2024:data-protection-registration-certificate-3p-learning-uk-limited.pdf))
    * The United States Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) and Rule  
        as administered by the Federal Trade Commission
    * The United States Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”)
    * The Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act
    * The Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (“PIPEDA”)
    * The Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (British Columbia) (“FIPPA”)
    * The Personal Information International Disclosure Protection Act (Nova Scotia) (“PIIDPA”)
    * The Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act, Ontario (“MFIPPA”)
    * The Student Online Personal Information Protection Act, California (“SOPIPA”)
    * The EU General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation 2016/679)(“GDPR”)
    * The UK General Data Protection Regulation (“UK GDPR”)
    * The South African Protection of Personal Information Act (‘POPI Act’).

What personal information we collect
------------------------------------

* We collect personal information to provide Registrants our learning products, services and related information.  The kinds of personal information we collect depends on how you interact with us. 

* We collect the following categories of personal information:
    * As a customer, prospective customer, or user of our Site, we may collect information such as your name, contact information including phone number and email address, school name, class year and country or state of residence or school. 
    * We may also collect details of other interactions that you have with us, together with any other information that you choose to provide us with, for example, through your interactions with our customer and technical support teams. 
    * We do not however collect any unnecessary personal information from Registrants (for instance, information about religious beliefs). 
    * It is impractical in most circumstances for you to remain anonymous, and we may not be able to interact with you, provide access to the Site, or answer your enquiry if we are not able to identify you or collect your personal information. 
    * In the case of school/educational institution customers (**School Customer**), we seek consent from the School Customer to be provided with Registrant information for and on behalf of that student or teacher. 
    * In the case of individual / home subscriptions (**Home Customers**) we seek consent from the Home Customer at the time of purchasing and registering the product to use the information collected from them (including the student). Subscriptions on behalf of a student who is a minor must be completed by the student’s parent or legal guardian.

*  Registrants who do not give this consent (or do not have this consent provided on their behalf) cannot provide us with their personal information and cannot use the Site. You can however withdraw your consent at any time.

How we collect and process your personal information
----------------------------------------------------

* We may collect your personal information in a number of ways, including:
    * directly from you (unless it is unreasonable or impracticable to do so);
    * from our School Customer (e.g. teachers or school administrators that purchase access to our Site for their students and teachers); or
    * from third parties such as our distributors (resellers and sales agents).

### **General contact**

* You may provide us with personal information when you contact us via our websites, by email or by phone or through feedback surveys. The information you provide will assist us in responding to your enquiry, or you may provide information anonymously.

### Personal information for account subscription

* For Home Customers, the parent or carer registering on behalf of their child(ren), must give their consent at the time of registration to provide us with information about them and their child(ren) to use our Services. We are unable to provide access to Services to students under 13 years of age or who are legally a minor in their relevant location, without the parent or carer providing consent and details to administer the account subscription.
* For School Customers: Teachers or administrators registering for their class or school must give their consent at the time of registration to provide us with their own name, class name, school name and their email address to administer the school / education institution’s account, as well as student details (name, class, and age).
* We also ask for Registrants’ consent to use any personal information collected in accordance with this Privacy Policy at the time of login to our Site. If a Registrant does not wish to provide us with their consent, they are unable agree to the Site Terms and Conditions and must not use the Site.

### Personal information within in-program access

* The personal information or identifiers provided to us from the parent or teacher will be used in our programs to deliver our Services.
* The learning activities in our education programs may also allow personal information to be collected and processed as follows:
    * Students and teachers may access learning activities that allow a free-text response to be entered, for example, educational book review, writing exercises, or to note learning outcomes. The information may be viewed by the subscribed Registrants within their account permissions. The teacher or parent may give additional consents for competition activities that we administer.
    * Students may access learning activities for reading practice. Our program may collect voice-recordings of a student where a teacher has assigned a reading practice tasks (_school customers only_). Audio files can be deleted at any time and are automatically deleted after 24 months.
* In circumstances personal information is entered by the user, consent is given by School or Home Customer to 3P Learning to use the information to deliver and these learning activities.
* For School Customers, we do not enable additional services from third parties (such as class administration services) to collect or use personal information unless you have agreed to receive those services. In those circumstances the terms of the third party in relation to the collection and use of personal information will also apply.

### Careers

* You may provide us with personal information as an applicant, contractor or employee to discuss roles and careers at 3P Learning. You will receive our employer privacy statement and we will only use personal information for those discussions.

What we will do with your information
-------------------------------------

* The information collected from Registrants, customers or prospective customers may be used for the following purposes:
    * to provide access to our products and services;
    * to manage prospective purchases, purchased subscriptions and payments including to provide quotes or offers;
    * to send a confirmation notice to the Registrant of the registration; to administer and manage accounts, including password resetting, responding to questions raised by Registrants, to contact the Registrant about any problems with the Registrant’s account or conduct on the Site;
    * to receive updates about our products and services;
    * to send out a 3P Learning newsletter or emails about the Site including information about current events, changes, improvements, upgrades, new product development and rules of the Site;
    * to publish the names of winners and high performers on the Site or in the 3P Learning newsletter and to provide results data for each Registrant or school class;
    * to send prizes or certificates for participation and performance on the Site;
    * for administrative, planning, product or service development, staff training, quality control and research purposes relating to our products and services;
    * for marketing purposes, but only where we have express or implied consent to contact someone or we are otherwise permitted by law to do so. Registrants may also opt out at any time by following the specific opt out instructions within the communications that we send.
* Hall of Fame leaderboards: 3P Learning strives to provide a highly engaging Site for students. Given students have indicated their strong preference for their name to be shown publicly on our Sites in recognition of their achievements, we allow this – but we do not allow full names (i.e. First Name and Surname) to be shown publicly. In addition, all administrative user access to any Site permits the partial (to initials only) or full anonymising (by use of a pseudonym) of names, where preferred by the user. If you have any questions about the Hall of Fame and managing the information that is disclosed, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@3plearning.com).
* The Site does not provide students with any means to communicate directly with each other. There are no chat rooms connected with the learning resources. Access to, and use of customer feedback forums or our professional online communities, are designed and limited for use by parents, educators and/or other contributors who are not legally minors.
* The Site may have additional features in which parents and teachers can give their consent, and/or give consent on behalf of a student, to access, disclose or use their personal information or learning activity information.  

What we will not do with your personal information
--------------------------------------------------

* 3P Learning will keep your personal information confidential and not sell or disclose your information to advertisers or any external third parties, unless:
    * we believe, in good faith, that we are required to share your information with a third party such as a regulator or court in order to comply with law, regulation, legal process, court order or subpoena; 
    * to enforce our Terms & Conditions or the terms of the licence granted to access and use the Site;
    * the disclosure is to a third party that acts on our behalf, powers certain aspects of our Sites or processes data on our behalf, such as a distributor of our products and services, the licensor or owner of a product or resource that we distribute, or to a contracted service provider;
    * in connection with any transaction involving our companies or assets, where another party acquires ownership or operation of the Site, in which case that successor organization will be subject to the obligations in this Privacy Policy and any contractual representations we have entered into, and subject to law; or
    * to protect the safety and security of our Registrants and our Site.
* If third parties act on our behalf, we require them to hold, use and disclose your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, applicable privacy obligations and our contractual obligations. 
* Generally we will only use your information within 3P Learning, however, sometimes we provide data on results to government education departments, peak bodies managing or representing schools, or schools themselves, especially in the case of School Customers, who use the features of our products (such as performance reporting tools) for educational / teaching purposes. We will require these third parties to comply strictly with our instructions, use the information only for legitimate educational interests and not for any commercial purposes. 
* We do not sell data to advertisers (whether personal, anonymous or aggregated). We do not use data to engage in targeted advertising to children and we do not create or build personal profiles of students other than for the purpose of supporting authorized educational/school purposes or as otherwise specifically authorized by a parent/student or school/educational institution customer. 
* We do not use cookies or third party providers to engage in behavioural targeting of advertisements to students. For more information refer to our Cookies & Third Party Technologies Policy. 

How long we hold your information
---------------------------------

* We retain the personal information that we collect from and about our Registrants for as long as it is needed to provide access to the Site or to manage that Registrant’s account.
* We take reasonable steps to delete the personal information we collect if your registration to use our Site lapses and you (or if you are under 13 or legally a minor in your relevant location, a parent or guardian may request on your behalf) opt out of receiving further communications from us, or if you ask us to delete your information. We may however retain and use personal information as necessary to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations, to resolve disputes and to enforce our agreements, and we may retain and use anonymous and aggregated information for performance reporting, benchmarking and analytic purposes and for product and service improvement.
* Registrants can request that their personal information be deleted by contacting us:  
    For Reading Eggs/Mathseeds products: [dpo@3plearning.com](mailto:dpo@3plearning.com)  
    For other products: [privacy@3plearning.com](mailto:privacy@3plearning.com)

Updating and accessing your personal information
------------------------------------------------

* Registrants have a right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about them, and Registrants can also update their personal information at any time, in each case by contacting 3P Learning.
* If you wish to receive a copy of this information or to update or correct information held about you, please address your request to the Privacy and Data Protection Officers at privacy@3plearning.com. We will endeavour to deal with your request promptly.

Keeping your personal information secure
----------------------------------------

* 3P Learning is committed to information security. We will use all reasonable endeavours to keep the personal information we collect and use in a secure environment, and we have implemented appropriate technical, administrative and physical security measures that are designed to protect personal information from unauthorised access, disclosure, use and modification. These measures include the encryption of personal information and the implementation of organisational measures, such as our incident response plan. As part of our privacy compliance processes we review these security procedures to consider appropriate new technology and methods and engage independent third parties to review and audit aspects of our information security. 
* We use Microsoft Azure and Amazon Web Services for data hosting and storage as set out in the table below. Both providers are recognised for their leading approaches to data security.
* |     | Where data is hosted |     | (Backup) |
    | --- | --- | --- | --- |
    | Reading Eggs, Mathseeds, Wordflyers, Writing legends | AWS | US  | (Australia) |
    | Mathletics | Microsoft Azure | US  | (West Europe) |
    | Writing Legends, Storyathon | Microsoft Azure | Australia and US. | (West Europe) |
    | Brightpath Progress | AWS | Australia | (Australia (Vic)) |
    
* Further information regarding Microsoft Azure privacy and security practices, including the latest updates and compliance information, at [news.microsoft.com/security2015](http://news.microsoft.com/security2015) and [www.microsoft.com/en-us/trustcenter/security/azure-security](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/trustcenter/security/azure-security).
* Further information regarding Amazon Web Services privacy and security practices, including the latest updates and compliance information, can be found at [aws.amazon.com/compliance/data-privacy-faq](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/data-privacy-faq/) and [aws.amazon.com/security](https://aws.amazon.com/security/)
* We provide our personnel with training about data security and privacy, and we require all our employees and contractors to comply with this Privacy Policy and their obligations of confidentiality. We will take appropriate actions to address breaches by employees and contractors of the obligations imposed by this Privacy Policy.

Data transfers, storage and processing globally
-----------------------------------------------

* Registrants’ personal information is uploaded to and stored on servers that are maintained by third party providers, Microsoft Azure and Amazon Web Services, at locations in the United States, Europe and Australia. For further information about where personal information is hosted please see our [Data Privacy and Security FAQs](https://pppmarketingcdn.blob.core.windows.net/docs/global/policy/2024:04:3p-learning-data-privacy-security-faqs.pdf).
* As we operate globally, we may on occasion allow your personal information to be accessed in countries other than your own location. We may do this where data is accessed:
    * by companies within the 3P Group (i.e. 3P Learning Limited, Blake eLearning and their related entities and subsidiaries) for operational, administrative and compliance purposes;
    * by our sales, operational or global customer support teams (primarily, although not exclusively, located in Australia, the United Kingdom, the USA and Canada); or
    * by one of our licensors (who owns, develops and hosts a particular product) or distributors (sales agents or resellers) who requires the information to set up, service or manage a customer account;
    * where a copy is sent to the Registrant itself at their request.
* By consenting to the collection and use of their personal information, Registrants’ consent to their personal information being transferred and stored in this manner.
* Registrants in Canada, please refer to ‘Special information for users across Canada’.  
* Registrants in the EU and UK, please refer to ‘Special information for users in the European Union and the United Kingdom’. 
* We may record, with your express consent, calls with customers for quality and staff training purposes. If, with your consent, we record a telephone call for this purpose, that recording will be stored in data centres located in US and deleted when no longer required. 

Anonymous or aggregated information
-----------------------------------

* In addition to personal information and results data, 3P Learning also collects anonymous information about Registrants and the activities of Registrants on the Site. Anonymous information is information that is not linked to the name or identity of a user. This information is used for educational performance reporting and analytics and to assist us in enhancing the learning resources. The information remains anonymous at all times.
* 3P Learning powers certain elements of the Company’s online marketing and advertising using information from third-party service providers that already know about you (referred to as ‘retargeting’). We collect information about where you saw the ads and what ads you clicked on. This is data that does not personally or directly identify you. We do not engage in this type of marketing or advertising to students or children.
* When agreeing to the Term and Conditions, Registrants grant us the right to use this anonymous information for our own purposes, such as the preparation of statistical reports or to improve and change the content of our products.
* You can find more information on cookies and website technologies in our ‘Cookies & Third Party Technologies Policy’.

Revision of Privacy Policy
--------------------------

3P Learning reserves the right to change, modify, or revise this Privacy Policy in order to comply with any applicable laws, to reflect changes in our processes or for any other reason at any time.

We will notify Registrants when we update this Privacy Policy by publishing our notification on this website. We also communicate important changes in our Privacy Policy to Registered Users and customers during their subscription term.

By accessing our learning Sites or websites you consent to the terms under which we process your information set out in this Privacy Policy, including how we notify you of amendments to this Privacy Policy.

Contact Us
----------

All requests to access, update and delete personal information as well as questions and concerns about your personal information and this Privacy Policy should be directed as follows:

For Reading Eggs/Mathseeds products: [dpo@3plearning.com](mailto:dpo@3plearning.com)  
For other products: [privacy@3plearning.com](mailto:privacy@3plearning.com)

If you have a question or a complaint you can also write to us at Privacy Officer 3P Learning,  655 Parramatta Road,  Leichhardt, NSW, Australia 2040

We will endeavor to respond to your query as quickly as possible. 

If you are not satisfied with the response you receive, you may have the right to contact the regulator responsible for privacy in your home country.

To contact us by phone, please find the contact numbers to our customer support office on the last page of this policy.

Special information for users across Canada
-------------------------------------------

* 3P Learning is committed to providing access to our resources through an environment that is compliant with all national and provincial privacy requirements applicable to us, and those requirements that apply to our School Customers across Canada.
* This Privacy Policy has been developed with the standards required to be compliant with the Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act, the Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA), the Personal Information International Disclosure Protection Act (Nova Scotia) (“PIIDPA”), the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (British Columbia) (“FIPPA”) and the Municipal Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act, Ontario (“MFIPPA”).
* Information that is located outside Canada will adhere and be subject to legal requirements in those foreign countries. We review and respond to requirements according to the laws applicable to us and our service providers.
* **For School Customers – Mathletics**  Our customer service team in Canada administers student data for Mathletics for Canadian school customers.  Accordingly, student names remain in Canada for this service. The data pertaining to a student’s activity within the platform (non-personally identifiable data) is stored in the East US 2 region of Microsoft Azure, and backed up in West Europe.  Access to data is restricted to users with approved access to 3P applications. The School may approve teachers, administration and IT personnel to access information (including student information) held in the school account. 

        Schools may request that their users in a class are identified by pseudonyms rather than names to access our products and resources. 

        Please contact our Privacy Officer if you require additional information at:  
        Privacy Officer, 3P Learning, 655 Parramatta Road, Leichhardt, NSW 2040 Australia, or [privacy@3plearning.com](mailto:privacy@3plearning.com).  

        If you have any further questions or would like to contact us by telephone regarding the above: please visit our [Contact Us](https://www.3plearning.com/contact/) page for details.

Special Information for users in the European Union and the United Kingdom
--------------------------------------------------------------------------

* 3P Learning welcomes the EU GDPR and UK GDPR as essential regulations to affirm our commitment to data protection across the European Union and the United Kingdom. We are committed to ensuring:
    * Personal data is processed fairly, lawfully and in a transparent manner
    * Personal data is collected and processed only for specified and lawful purposes
    * Processed data is adequate, relevant and not excessive
    * Processed data is accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date
    * Personal data is not kept longer than necessary
    * Personal data is processed in accordance with an individual’s rights
    * Personal data is kept secure
    * Personal data is not transferred to countries outside of the EU or the UK without adequate protection
* The information below should be read in addition to our Privacy Policy, and outlines specific information relevant to certain aspects of our GDPR compliance.
* 3P Learning UK Ltd is registered with the Independent Commissioners Office (ICO), registration reference no: **Z2188515.** A copy of this certificate can be downloaded [here](https://pppmarketingcdn.blob.core.windows.net/docs/global/policy/2024:data-protection-registration-certificate-3p-learning-uk-limited.pdf). 3P Learning UK Ltd is a company registered in England and Wales with company registration no. 05919214 and is a trading company within the 3P Learning Group.
* Lawfulness of processing: 3P Learning collects personal information in a number of contexts and for a number of purposes. Please refer to the “What personal information we collect”, “What we will do with your information” and “How we collect and process your information” sections of the Privacy Policy. Our processing activities are based either on consent or legitimate interests pursued by 3P Learning and our school and district customers in delivering learning resources for use by schools, teachers, parents and students which are designed to improve learning outcomes and inspire a love of learning.
* Is personal information transferred outside of the European Union or the United Kingdom? Yes, personal information in relation to Registrants located in the EU or the UK may be transferred outside of the EU or UK in two main situations:
    * User data may be uploaded to and stored on our servers located in the USA or Australia. For further information about where personal information is hosted please see our [Data Privacy and Security FAQs](https://pppmarketingcdn.blob.core.windows.net/docs/global/policy/2024:04:3p-learning-data-privacy-security-faqs.pdf)
    * Additional information about Microsoft’s compliance with the EU GDPR is available [here](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/TrustCenter/Privacy/gdpr/default.aspx).
    * Additional information about Amazon Web Services’ compliance with the EU GDPR is available [here](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/gdpr-center/).
    * In most instances, personal data about our EU and UK based customers is collected, accessed and managed by our sales, operational and customer support teams in the United Kingdom. Very occasionally however, such information may be shared with our employees in one of our offices outside of the UK e.g. to respond to an urgent customer support query outside of normal hours or for internal reporting processes. Our main offices outside of the EU and UK are located in Calgary, Canada and Sydney, Australia. To ensure appropriate safeguards exist in relation to such transfers, 3P Learning has implemented [standard contractual clauses](https://commission.europa.eu/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection/standard-contractual-clauses-scc_en) to cover the transfer of data relevant to EU and UK registrants to other companies within the 3P Group that are not located in the EU.
    * We stay up to date with regulatory developments in the EU and the UK to ensure that appropriate and compliant safeguards are in place for the transfer of any personal information outside of the EU or UK.
* Additionally, please refer to information about our Hall of Fame.
* For further information, please contact the 3P Learning Data Protection and Privacy Officers, whose details are as below:  
    For Reading Eggs/Mathseeds products: [dpo@3plearning.com](mailto:dpo@3plearning.com)  
    For other products: [privacy@3plearning.com](mailto:privacy@3plearning.com)

If you have any further questions or would like to contact us by telephone regarding the above: please visit our [Contact Us](https://www.3plearning.com/contact/?) page for details.

More privacy information
------------------------

* For more information on privacy legislation and guidelines in your local jurisdiction please contact your relevant local authorities.
    * Australia: [privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/)
    * Canada: [priv.gc.ca/en](https://www.priv.gc.ca/en)
    * European Union: [gdpr.eu](http://ec.europa.eu/justice_home/fsj/privacy)
    * India: [meity.gov.in/](https://www.meity.gov.in/)
    * New Zealand: [privacy.org.nz](http://www.privacy.org.nz/)
    * Singapore: [pdpc.gov.sg](https://www.pdpc.gov.sg/)
    * United Kingdom: [ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/)
    * USA: [ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/)
    * South Africa: [popia.co.za](https://popia.co.za/)

Cookies & Third Party Technologies Policy
-----------------------------------------

22 April 2024

This section explains how 3P Learning Limited and its group entities (**3P Learning** or **we**) use cookies and third party technologies on our websites (**Websites**), web and mobile apps, and in online products and services that we own, operate and distribute, including Mathletics, Mathseeds, Reading Eggs, Word Flyers, Writing Legends, Storyathon, Teachers Workshop Series and Brightpath Progress (**Services**). It explains what these technologies are and why we use them, and how to contact us with any questions concerning our use of cookies or third party technologies.

What are cookies?
-----------------

A cookie is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. When you visit the site again, the cookie allows that site to recognize your browser. Cookies perform various tasks, including remembering your preferences, and are an important part of improving your experience of our Websites and Services.

We use cookies and third party technologies for several reasons, including:

* for technical reasons in order for our Websites and Services to operate;
* to store user preferences and other information to save you time, or tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page;
* to enable functionality and personalisation to provide an improved user experience;
* to track and target the interests of our users (such as parents and/or school teachers and administrators), to help us understand how our Websites are being used or how effective our marketing campaigns are, or to help us customise our Websites for you to deliver customized content and promotions to customers or users whose behaviour indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area;
* third party cookies through our Websites and Services for advertising, analytics and other purposes. This is described in more detail below.

We **do not** use cookies or third party providers to engage in behavioural targeting of advertisements to students.

You may manage how you accept or block cookies in the browser settings or settings of your device (see further below for more information).

What cookies do we use?
-----------------------

When you visit our Websites, wee use the following cookies:

* **Essential website cookies.** These are cookies that are required for the operation of our Website, Services and the use of their features. The information collected relates to the operation of our Website and Services (e.g. website scripting language and security tokens) and enables us to provide you with the service you have requested. In most cases these are session cookies and are deleted when you close your browser. Some may persist for up to 48 hrs to up to 13 months improve the experience for users that log back into the Services within a short range of periods of logging out.
* **Analytical / performance cookies.** These cookies collect information on how users use our Website, for example which pages you visit most often, whether you receive any error messages and how you arrived at our website. Information collected by these cookies is used to improve your use of our Website and Services. These cookies expire after a period of inactivity.
* **Functionality cookies.**  These cookies are used to enhance the functionality of our Websites and Services, to improve your user experience by remembering the choices you have made when interacting with our websites and online products. In most cases these cookies are persistent cookies and remain stored, in order to recall your preferences, until you clear your cache.
* **Advertising cookies.** These cookies are used to make advertising messages more relevant to the user of the Website and are based on the user’s browser settings. They perform functions like preventing the same ad from continuously reappearing, ensuring that ads are properly displayed for advertisers, and in some cases selecting ads that are based on your interests. In most cases these cookies expire within 90 days but can persist up to 13 months. We do not use cookies to engage in behavioural targeting of advertisements to students.

**Additional information about third party cookies**
----------------------------------------------------

Some of the third party cookies we use on our Website include:

* Cookies to monitor web traffic and analysis services. We use Google Analytics, LinkedIn and Microsoft page analytics services to help us understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. Cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content. Generally, all the information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous.
* Cookies that allow the provision of enhanced functionality and personalisation, such as videos.
* Cookies used for advertising and marketing purposes to promote our Services and/or provide aggregated data to help us review our digital content. We may engage the services of Google AdWords, LinkedIn and Meta/Facebook.

The data and insights we obtain from third party technologies are used by 3P Learning companies to help us deliver our services.

Other third party technologies
------------------------------

Other third party applications and services may be used to add features to our Website or Servies, or to gauge the effectiveness of our website and marketing campaigns.  These may include but are not limited to: 

* plug ins that help us better understand our site visitors and app users
* technologies to support the internal operations of our business
* services to allow users to share content on social media platforms – for example, to share a news article from our public website . We sometimes contract third-party service providers, vendors, SDKs or plug ins to assist us in better understanding our site visitors and app users. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help support the internal operations of our business.
* To find out more about the third party services, refer to our [Data Privacy and Security FAQs.](https://pppmarketingcdn.blob.core.windows.net/docs/global/policy/2024:04:3p-learning-data-privacy-security-faqs.pdf)

IP Addresses
------------

Additionally, when visitors request pages from our Websites and Services, 3P Learning’s servers log the visitor’s internet protocol address (“**IP address**”). Your IP address, browser type, browser language, and the date and time of your query, enable us to better understand and improve the usability, performance and effectiveness of our websites for purposes of system administration, to infer a visitor’s geographic location, to track the use of our websites, and to identify a visitor when 3P Learning feels it is necessary to enforce compliance with our policies.

How can I manage cookies?
-------------------------

Most internet browsers are set up by default to accept cookies. However you can manage or disable cookies and you can find instructions for the following browers here: [Microsoft Edge,](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/delete-and-manage-cookies-168dab11-0753-043d-7c16-ede5947fc64d) [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en), [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enhanced-tracking-protection-firefox-desktop?redirectslug=enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences&redirectlocale=en-US) and [Safari](https://support.apple.com/en-au/guide/safari/sfri11471/mac). Keep in mind that if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including necessary cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our Website and Services and some functionality may be restricted.

You can find more information about cookies, including how to disable them at  [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

In addition, most advertising networks offer you a way to opt out of targeted advertising. If you would like to find out more information, please visit  [www.aboutads.info/choices.](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)

You may opt out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/) or if located in the European Union, by clicking [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You may continue to receive generic advertisements.

Mobile App technologies
-----------------------

Our mobile Apps deliver access to a range of learning programs. We use technologies to support how the App operates and to check the performance of the App. You can review the App details, including the permissions settings that you consent to, before installing the App on your device.

If you have any further questions, please contact us.

Privacy Officer
---------------

Privacy@3plearning.com

3P Learning Ltd

655 Parramatta Road,

Leichhardt, Sydney,

NSW, 2040, Australia

##### For Telephone details please see below:

### Other Enquiries:

| **Asia Pacific** | **Australia** | **Asia** |
| --- | --- | --- |
|     | Telephone +61 290192800  <br>Fax +61 282145869 | +612 9019 2800  <br>customerservice@3plearning.asia |
|     | **New Zealand** | **Pakistan** |
|     | 0800 375 327  <br>customerservice@3plearning.co.nz | +92 111 44 33 55  <br>cs.pk@3plearning.com |
| **Europe, Africa and  <br>Middle East** | **UK and Europe** | **Middle East** |
|     | Existing Customers  <br>+44 117 370 1990  <br>support@3plearning.co.uk  <br>  <br>New Enquiries  <br>+44 117 370 1578  <br>registrations@3plearning.co.uk | Existing Customers  <br>+44 117 370 1990  <br>  <br>New Enquiries  <br>+44 117 370 1578  <br>middleeast@3plearning.com |
|     | **Africa** |     |
|     | +27 (0)11 7068959  <br>customerservice@3plearning.co.za |     |
| **Across the Americas** | **Canada** | **Mexico and Peru** |
|     | +1 877 467 6851  <br>customerservice@3plearning.ca | +52 557 827 9581  <br>info@quipus.mx |
|     | **USA** | **Latin America  <br>and the Caribbean** |
|     | +1 866 387 9139  <br>Existing Customers  <br>support.usa@3plearning.com  <br>New Enquiries  <br>info.usa@3plearning.com | +1 866 387 9139  <br>support.usa@3plearning.com |

**Skip to**

Better ways to learn

©2020–2024 3P Learning.  
All rights reserved.

* Who We Help
* Subjects
* Programs
* Support

Follow us

* Sign in

* For Educators
* Packages
* Subjects
* Company
* Support
